SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR/ NETWORK ENGINEER

PROFILE

Accomplished IT & Communications specialist with experience working on deployed military networks both as a field technician and in 2nd/3rd line support roles. **Provides** exceptional troubleshooting and problem-solving skills to the highest standard, supporting an array of systems in high pressure environments.

Consummate professional who demonstrates high levels of business acumen, understands business demands and consistently delivers client solutions, whilst streamlining processes to optimise response time and ensure the attainment of Service Level Agreements.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Virtualisation: VMWare, vSphere, Hyper-V, Remote Desktop

Microsoft: Windows Desktop 7,8,10, Windows Server 2003,2008,2012R2, Microsoft Exchange 2003,2012, Active Directory, Group Policy Management, Microsoft Office Suite 365

Networking: IPv4 & IPv6, LAN & WAN, VLAN, DHCP, DNS, Cisco IOS, Vocality Routing

Miscellaneous: Netcool, Symantec Backup Exec, McAfee Antivirus, ePolicy Orchestrator, SCOM, Remedy/CASD Incident Reporting

KEVIN BRUNNEYE

York/Leeds 07547251617

kevinbrunneye@hotmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/kevinbrunneye

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Cisco CCNA CyberOps SECFND
- City & Guilds Advanced Fibre Optics Cabling Level 2
- Defence Information Infrastructure (Land Restricted/Secret)
- Harris PRC 117F Radio Maintainer
- Global Interconnected Network (Deployable) Maintainer
- Swe-Dish (CCT-120) Satellite Terminal Maintainer
- MTA (Expected completion April 2020)
- MCSA Windows Server 2012 (Expected Completion Oct 2020)

*Security Clearance: DV Security Cleared - Details Upon Request

EDUCATION

- BTEC Level 3 Diploma in Professional Competence for IT and Telecoms Professionals
- Advanced Apprenticeship for IT, Software, Telecoms & Web Professionals (Defence College of Communication and Information Systems)
- BA History Degree (2:1) University of Hull
- 2 A-Levels & 10 GCSEs (Grades A C)
- IT GNVQ (A,B,B,B,B)

PERSONAL

- Rugby League fan, with a love of playing and watching most sports
- Passionate music fan who plays guitar, keyboard and drums
- Reading/studying with a focus of self-development and improving my technical knowledge
- Organising social events and activities, to encourage team cohesion

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

Commercial Sales Executive

Hull FC Super League Ltd. Nov 2013 - Oct 2014

- Enhanced revenue streams by promoting the club to businesses and establishing new commercial links
- Collaborated with the communications and marketing team to promote club products to businesses and fans

Sales & Technical Service Advisor TalkTalk/ClearAnswer Ltd. Jun 2012 - Oct 2013

- Served as POC for TalkTalk broadband customers and delivered guidance to support technical issues
- Continuous monitoring and leadership of the sales team to ensure all KPI's were met
- Managed and developed a team of 12 agents through a variety of motivational and analytical techniques
- Identified training and development needs through job analysis, appraisal schemes and regular 1-2-1s

REFERENCES

References available upon request

MOST RECENT EMPLOYMENT

Royal Air Force ICT Technician

90 Signals Unit Tactical Communications Wing (TCW) Nov 2014 – Present

TCW is a deployable communications unit responsible for deploying around the world on short notice to design, create and implement highly advanced IT solutions for a large number of users, providing systems with the ability to provide mission critical information. The maintenance and fault rectification of these systems are paramount to the successful completion of a military deployment. A brief summary of my role and experience includes the following:

- Manage UK based and deployed systems, ensuring smooth handling of incidents and requests across a wide range of software, services and systems.
- Plan, deploy, administer and withdraw communications networks of over 500 users
- Accountable for server administration including user creation, security permissions, group policy management, fault finding and system updates
- Maintain vast networks of workstations, diagnosing and repairing issues with laptops, printers, telephones and peripherals
- Deliver 3rd line SPOC duty whilst at 15 Signals
 Regiment Service Management Centre, including
 remote administration of nodes in Iraq, Cyprus,
 Crete, Afghanistan and UK
- Continuous monitoring of communication links using SCOM, NetCool and CA Spectrum
- Complete key tasks such as scheduled maintenance, GAL imports/exports, data archiving and failover procedures testing
- Configure system backups and develop CIS Disaster Recovery Plans
- Develop and test new procedures such as maintenance checks and local work instructions with the aim of enhancing efficiency and operational output
- Infrastructure installations such as cross site fibre links, copper cabling, satellite dishes and LOS masts
- Termination and repair of cabling using test equipment (cable testers, OTDR, LSPM) and both mechanical and fusion splicing
- Manage and coach junior members of the team, delivering guidance on how to resolve complex faults